# **Abdelfatah Ashour**

# **Frontend Developer**

Alexandria, Egypt +201120974272

abdelfatahashour4@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdelfatah-ashour

Portfolio: <a href="https://abdelfatah-ashour-portfolio.vercel.app">https://abdelfatah-ashour-portfolio.vercel.app</a>

# **Summary**

To seek and maintain a full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, excellent time management, and problem-solving skills. Experienced working with teams to produce impactful, leading-edge websites that engage customers and deliver business results. Well-versed in design standards and user preferences.

# **Work Experience**

### Frontend Developer

Flowtechtics | Alexandria, Egypt

October 2021 – Present

- Implemented and deployed entries web applications for more than +3 projects with React JS, Next JS, Redux, TypeScript, and Firebase.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies using Redux and Redux/toolkit.
- Created reusable React components for the date picker, dropdown, buttons, and input styles according to the provided designs. and implement custom hooks for parsing user agents, query URLs, translation, protecting routes, and fetching APIs.
- Integrated are third-party packages like (Firebase cloud messaging & O2Auth & Charts JS).
- Handled errors in all cases to be friendly for users as a user experience.

#### Frontend Developer

Remotely | Alexandria, Egypt

June 2022 – August 2022

- Joined a team located in Cairo remotely part-time. And I implemented +2 business requirements in a project about virtual classes online (joined at last 4 sprints and using agile methodology).
- Build custom components UI with Chakra UI and Tailwind CSS with animation, Implemented and integrated business
  requirements like Behaviors groups and Questions Group as a Components UI and APIs using apollo-graphql for CRUD
  operations.

#### Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Sass
- React JS
- React Native (in progress)

- Next JS
- Redux
- @Redux/toolkit
- Webpack
- Jest
- @testing/Library
- GraphQL

- Socket-IO
- Git and GitHub
- OOP (Object-oriented Programming)
- FP (Functional Programming)
- SOLID
- Problem Solving

# **Projects**

## Krafttopia: ( https://krafttopia.com )

 Overview: E-commerce and panels dashboard web application using React JS, Redux, Material UI, Firebase Cloud Messing, and OAuth2.0.

# Port-flash: ( https://www.port-flash.online )

Overview: Transportation and logistics web application React JS, @Redux/toolkit, and Material UI.

## React-honey-hooks: ( https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-honey-hooks )

- Source code: ( https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/react-honey-hooks ).
- Overview: React custom hooks.

## Freedom Blogs: ( http://express-x-you.vercel.app )

- Source code: ( https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/express-x-you ).
- Overview: Blog's web application using Next JS, Context API, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB.

# Brakt: ( <a href="https://brakt.vercel.app">https://brakt.vercel.app</a>)

- Source code: ( https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/brakt ).
- Overview: Blog's web application using React JS, Redux, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB.

## Sola: ( <a href="https://sola.vercel.app">https://sola.vercel.app</a>)

- Source code: ( <a href="https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/sola">https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/sola</a> ).
- Overview: Chat web application (Real-time) using React JS, Redux, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB, and Socket-IO.

#### Express-x-you: ( http://express-x-you.vercel.app )

- Source code: ( https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/express-x-you ).
- Overview: E-commerce web application using Next JS, Redux, Node JS, Express JS, and MongoDB.

# **Education**

Bachelor's Degree, Faculty of Law

Alexandria University, October 2013 - May 2019

# **Personal Information**

Birth of date: 16/12/1994

Military status: postponement

Languages:

Arabic: Native

English: Conversation